Register to the Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii Papers
1916-1985
2008C47
Hoover Institution Archives
34 microfilm reels (5 linear feet)
Correspondence, consular and financial records, writings, personal documents, printed matter, and photographs, relating to the Russian emigration. Used for a Zarubezhnaia Rus' exhibit. Includes some papers of V. K. Abdank-Kossovskii.
Abdank-Kossovskii, Vladimir Konkordovich, d. 1962, collector.
Access
The collection is open for research
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008
Alternative Forms of Material Available
A portion of the collection is available on Microfilm
Location of Original Materials
Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Chronology
1885 June 16 Born, Vitebsk Guberniia, Russia
1921 Author, Sila i chelovek, Sovremennaia nemetskaia mysl': sbornik statei
1922 Arrived in Paris, France, from Tunis, Tunisia
1922-1962 Journalist in the Russian émigré press
1962 April 19 Died, Grasse, France
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers consist primarily of materials collected by Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii for the exhibit "Zarubezhnaia Rus'," which chronicled the fate and life of Russian émigrés beginning in 1916 up to 1961.
Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii was a graduate of the Lazarevskii institut vostochnykh iazykov, the Aleksandrovskoe voennoe uchilishche, the Ofitserskaia elektrotekhnicheskaia shkola, and the Istoriko-filologichskii fakul'tet Novorossiiskii University.
Within the Zarubezhnaia Rus' File, the chronological file includes clippings, original documents, photographs, and print materials, providing information on the Russian diaspora in different countries, arranged by V. K. Abdank-Kossovskii himself, and pasted to album sheets. These materials were exhibited by Abdank-Kossovskii regularly in Paris. The subject file of the Zarubezhnaia Rus' File includes materials prepared by Abdank-Kossovskii for inclusion in the "Zarubezhnaia Rus'" exhibit, but categorized only by subject and not pasted for exhibit. These papers focus on all aspects of émigré existence, including Russian military and veteran organizations, Russian Orthodoxy, cultural, political and social organizations, literary life, and performing arts.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into eight series: Biographical file, Correspondence, Speeches and writings, Zarubezhnaia Rus' File, Photographs, Oversize file, Subject file, and Printed matter
Biography
Vladimir Abdank-Kossovskii was born in Vitebskaia guberniia, Russia, on June 16, 1885. He was educated in the Lazarevskii institut vostochnykh iazykov, the Aleksandrovskoe voennoe uchilishche, the Ofitserskaia elektrotekhnicheskaia shkola, and the History and Philology Department of the Imperatorskii Novorossiiskii universitet.
During World War I, Abdank-Kossovskii, who served as an engineer officer, received several medals for his service, including the St. George Cross and the Order of St. Anna. He then enlisted in the White Army; after the end of the Civil War he was evacuated to Tunis. In the early 1920s, he arrived in France, where he became active in Russian émigré monarchist organizations. Sharing the fate of numerous émigrés unable to find employment in their profession, Abdank-Kossovskii found work in factories and as a cab driver in Paris.
Being interested in journalism, Abdank-Kossovskii frequently contributed to Vozrozhdenie and other Russian émigré newspapers and was thus able to indulge his passion for Russian history and the fate of the Russian diaspora. He began collecting materials on the lives of Russian émigrés on different continents and established an exhibit entitled “Zarubezhnaia Rus’,” which chronicled the fate of Russians abroad from 1916 to 1961.
Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii died on April 19, 1962, in Grasse, France.
Russia--Emigration and immigration.
- Biographical File, 1954-1985. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes family correspondence, obituaries, and refugee questionnaire. Arranged by physical form
  - Family correspondence, 1962-1985 and undated. (Folder 1: 1)
    Includes letters from V. K. Abdank-Kossovskii to Svetlana and Venedikt Kossovsky (photocopy), from Venedikt Kossovsky to Sergei P. Polonsky, and condolence letter from Grand Duke Vladmir Kirillovich (photocopy)
  - Obituaries, 1962. (Folder 1: 2)
    Clippings
  - Questionnaire from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Refugee department, 1954 and undated. (Folder 1: 3)
    Includes biographical data
- Correspondence, 1934-1960 and undated.
  General note
  See also Biographical File
  Letters, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1: 4)
  - Bulatsel', Sergei Sergeevich, 1956-1960. (Folder 1: 5)
    Includes "V persidskoi kazachei ego velichestva Shakha divizii," 1957. Holograph
  - Danilevich, Tatiana Nikolaevna, 1956. (Folder 1: 6)
    Includes "Pod vpechatleniem," 1956, "Rus' bogatyrskaia i radost' bytiia," 1956, "Spiashchaia krasavitsa," 1954. Typescript
  - De Clapiers Collongues, Olga, 1944-1956 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Gornyi, Sergei.
    See Otsup, Aleksandr
  - Gogina, Ol'ga Vasilievna, 1935 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Isaenko, Evgeniia S., 1958 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Kletnova, Ekaterina Nikolaevna, 1934 (Folder 1: 10)
  - Markov, Anatolii L'vovich, 1951-1956 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Nikulins, Teopont E., 1956 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Otsup, Aleksandr (pseudonym Sergei Gornyi), 1934 (Folder 1: 13)
  - Pastac, Isaak Abramovich, 1944 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Rantanen, N., 1944 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Savin, N., 1957 (Folder 1: 16)
  - Strakhovsky, Leonid Ivanovich, undated (Folder 1: 17)
  - Sviatoslavskii, N., undated (Folder 1: 18)
  - Volzhenskii, Aleksei Mitrofanovich, 1944 (Folder 1: 19)
  - Vuich, Georgii Ivanovich, 1944 (Folder 1: 20)
- Speeches and Writings, 1947-1957 and undated.
  Arranged chronologically by title
  - General
    - Newspaper articles, 1947 and undated. (Folder 1: 21)
      Published mainly in Rossiia
    - Notes, 1956 and undated (Folder 1: 22)
  - "Anna Iaroslavna v Sandisie,", undated. (Folder 1: 23)
    Typescript
  - "Chudo chelovecheskikh predpriiatii,", undated. (Folder 1: 24)
  - "Ko dniu proslavleniia sv. kniazia Vladimira,", undated. (Folder 1: 25)
  - "Ko dniu sv. ravnoaposol'nago kniazia Vladimira,", undated. (Folder 1: 26)
  - "Mozhno bylo terpiet' stavku Batyia, no 'Leningrad' nel'zia preterpiet',", undated. (Folder 1: 27)
  - "O russkom ofitsere,", undated. (Folder 1: 28)
  - "O tom kak tsar' Ivan Vasil'evich Groznyi gotovilsia emigrirovat' v Angliiu,", undated. (Folder 1: 29)
    Typescript, incomplete. Includes newspaper clipping related to topic
  - "O voinie,", undated. (Folder 1: 30)
    Typescript with handwritten notes
  - "O zachatii i zdanii tsarstvuiushchago grada S.-Peterburga v lieto ot pervago dnia Adama 7211 po Rozhdestvie Iisusa Khrista 1703 goda,", undated. (Folder 1: 31)
  - "Paradiz Petra,", undated. (Folder 1: 32)
    Typescripts
  - "Peterburgu byt' pustu,", undated. (Folder 1: 33)
  - "Vasil'evskii ostrov,", undated. (Folder 1: 34)
    Holograph
  - "K predstoiashchemu iubileiu Sankt-Peterburga,", 1953. (Folder 1: 35)
  - "Fevral'skoe prestuplenie 1917-1957," (Folder 1: 36)
- Zarubezhnaia Rus' File, 1916-1961.
  Materials chronicle the life of Russian émigrés in Europe, Africa, Asia, North and South America. Includes author's catalog of exhibit, description, chronological and subject files, advertisements, calling (visiting) cards, clippings, concert programs and announcements, consular documents, correspondence, drawings, food and rations cards, fundraising documents, obituaries, personal identification documents, printed matter, signed orders (by White Army generals Petr N. Vrangel', Evgenii K. Miller and others), photographs, and travel documents
  - General
    - Catalog, undated
      - Part I (Folder 1: 37)
      - Part II (Folder 1: 38)
    - List of periodicals and print materials originally held as part of V. K. Abdank-Kossovskii's "Zarubezhnaia Rus'" collection, but not part of the present papers, undated (Folder 1: 39)
    - Unkovskii, Vladimir N. Description of "Zarubezhnaia Rus'" exhibit, 1944. (Folder 1: 40)
      Printed copy
    - Negatives (8) of exhibit, undated.
      See Photographs
  - Chronological file
    - 1916-1920. (Box 2)
      Materials chronicle the fate of the Russian White Army in the North as well as the evacuation from the Crimea and refugee life. Also includes materials on Empress Maria Feodorovna
    - 1921. (Box 3)
      Includes materials on Russian refugee camps at Gallipoli, Lemnos, Sidi-Bishr (Egypt), the activities of the Russian Press Office and the Russian Consulate in Constantinople, the Russian Red Cross, the Russian National University in Paris, life at the sanatorium of the Russian Red Cross on the Adriatic Sea. Also includes original photographs of generals Petr N. Vrangel', Aleksandr P. Kutepov, Vladimir K. Vitkovksii, a signed photograph of General A. P. Bogaevskii
    - 1922-1924. (Box 4)
      Includes materials on Grand Dukes Nikolai Nikolaevich and Kirill Vladimirovich, Zinaida N. Gippius and Dmitri S. Merezhkovskii, documents signed by generals Petr N. Vrangel' and Aleksandr P. Kutepov
    - 1925-1927. (Box 5)
      Includes materials on the Institut St. Serge in Paris, Grand Duke Dmitri Pavlovich, Boris S. Koverda, Ivan S. Shmelev, Reverend Innokentii Seryshev, documents signed by generals Petr N. Vrangel' and Evgenii K. Miller, letters from Prince Vladimir A. Krasinskii to Vladimir K. Abdank-Kossovskii
    - 1928-1929. (Box 6)
      Includes materials on the editorial board of Vozrozhdenie, the Russian Christian Student Movement, the Gallipoli Society and other veterans organizations, cadet corps, Cossack dzhigit groups, Russian opera and theatre in Paris, Russian parishes in Belgrade, Boulogne-Biancoure and Ugine (France). Also includes clippings on the death and funerals of Empress Maria Feodorovna, Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich, and General Petr N. Vrangel'
    - 1929-1930. (Box 7)
      Includes materials on the Brotherhood of Russian Truth (Bratstvo Russkoi Pravdy), Russian ballet in Rio de Janeiro, cinema, Russian secondary schools, Russian chamber of commerce in Paris. Also includes materials on the kidnapping of General Aleksandr P. Kutepov, Grand Duke Kirill Vladimirovich, and rare photos of Metropolitan Antonii (Khrapovitskii) visiting a Russian Cadet Corps
    - 1930-1931. (Box 8)
      Includes materials on the Gallipoli Society, cadet corps, Russian soldiers in the French Foreign Legion, fundraising documents for the search for General Aleksandr P. Kutepov and his kidnappers, Alexander I. Kuprin's novel Iunkera, including a handwritten and signed excerpt from the novel
    - 1931-1932. (Box 9)
      Includes materials on the Russian All-Military Union (ROVS), Russian soldiers in the French Foreign Legion. Also includes a letter signed by Grand Duchess Olga Aleksandrovna
    - 1932-1933. (Box 10)
      Includes materials on Vozrozhdenie, Bishop Vladimir (Tikhonitskii), Rev. Innokentii Seryshev, Ivan A. Bunin (receipt of the Nobel Prize), Nikolai N. Golovin
    - 1934. (Box 11)
      Includes materials on Russian scouting organizations, Russian fascists in Brazil, the Sokol movement. Also includes materials on the murder of King Alexander I of Yugoslavia
    - 1934. (Box 12)
      Includes materials on literary circles in France and Eastern Europe, Nikolai K. Roerich, Rev. Innokentii Seryshev
    - 1934-1935. (Box 13)
      Includes materials on the Russian All-Military Union (ROVS), Count Mikhail N. Grabbe, Aleksander L. Kazem-Bek and the Mladorossy (Young Russians), Metropolitan Evlogii (Georgievskii)
    - 1935. (Box 14)
      Includes materials on the Kondakov Institute in Prague, and a memorial gathering in memory of Admiral Aleksandr V. Kolchak, attended by generals Anton I. Denikin and Evgenii K. Miller
    - 1935-1936. (Box 15)
      Includes a photograph of members of Platoff's Don Cossack choir with Metropolitan Evlogii (Georgievskii) and General Evgenii K. Miller
    - 1936-1937. (Box 16)
      Includes materials on Nikolai P. Afonskii's choir, Platoff's Don Cossack Choir, the Miss Russia pageant, Olga I. Preobrazhenskaia's ballet studio in Paris, the Russian All-Military Union (ROVS), the Russian Nobility Association in Paris. Also includes materials on the kidnapping of General Evgenii K. Miller, and the role of General Nikolai V. Skoblin and his wife Nadezhda V. Plevitskaia
    - 1937. (Box 17)
      Includes materials on Metropolitan Evlogii (Georgievskii), the kidnapping of General Evgenii K. Miller, General Nikolai V. Skoblin, Sergei N. Tretiakov
    - 1937-1938. (Box 18)
      Includes materials on orphanages, the Russian cathedral in Shanghai, the Russian Church in China, General Dmitrii L. Khorvat, the kidnapping of General Evgenii K. Miller, and the court proceedings against Nadezhda V. Plevitskaia; Iakov L. Rubinshtein, Rev. Innokentii Seryshev
    - 1938-1939. (Box 19)
      Includes materials on celebrations of the 950th anniversary of the Baptism of Rus', the Russian cemetery at St. Genevieve-des-Bois near Paris. Also includes materials on grand dukes Kirill Vladimirovich and Vladimir Kirillovich, the funeral of Grand Duke Kirill Vladimirovich, Russian soldiers in General Francisco Franco's army
    - 1939-1940. (Box 20)
      Includes materials on the Alexander Nevsky cathedral in Paris, the Russian colony in Kharbin, Russian officers in the French Army, Russian writers in the diaspora. Also includes materials on Grand Duke Vladimir Kirillovich, Pavel N. Miliukov, Anastasii A. Vonsiatskii
    - 1940-1942. (Box 21)
      Includes materials on the official representation of Russian émigrés in France, the Russian nursing home "Maison Russe". Also includes materials on Grand Duke Vladimir Kirillovich, Vladimir K. Abdank-Kossovskii's project "Zarubezhnaia Rus'", Andrei F. Meiendorff, an original letter by Aleksei M. Remizov
    - 1942-1944. (Box 22)
      Includes Vladimir K. Abdank-Kossovskii's article "Rossiia v izgnanii", materials on Cossack divisions in the German army, the Council of Bishops of the Russian Orthodox Church Outside Russia in Vienna, descendants of Tsar Nicholas I in the diaspora, famous Russian émigrés deceased in France during the German occupation, Russian émigrés in the German Army, the Russian Liberation Army (ROA). Also includes materials on Grand Duke Vladimir Kirillovich, generals Petr N. Krasnov and Andrei A. Vlasov, Ekaterina P. Dostoevskaia, Iurii L. Voitsekhovskii
    - 1944-1946. (Box 23)
      Includes materials on Cossack divisions in the German army, Russian gypsies in France, the Russian Liberation Army (ROA). Also includes materials on Vladimir K. Abdank-Kossovskii, generals Anton I. Denikin, Petr N. Krasnov and Andrei A. Vlasov, metropolitans Anastasii (Gribanovskii), and Evlogii (Georgievskii).
    - 1946-1948. (Box 24)
      Includes materials on displaced persons camps, the Russian Museum in Prague, the Russian Orthodox parish in Vanves near Paris, Russian émigrés in the French resistance. Also includes materials on Vladimir K. Abdank-Kossovskii's arrest, Grand Duchess Olga Aleksandrovna, Grand Duke Vladimir Kirillovich
    - 1948-1949. (Box 25)
      Includes materials on the Museum and Archives of Russian Culture in San Francisco, the Russian All-Military Union (ROVS), the Russian Orthodox Church in Palestine, Vladimir K. Abdank-Kossovskii's exhibit "Zarubezhnaia Rus'", Grand Duke Vladimir Kirillovich
    - 1949-1950. (Box 26)
      Includes materials on Archbishop Ioann (Maksimovich), the Orthodox Church in America, the Russian Ecclesiastical Mission in the Holy Land
    - 1950-1951. (Box 27)
      Includes materials on displaced persons camps in Kellerberg and Schleissheim, the Eighth All American Sobor of the Russian Orthodox Greek Catholic Church, and the Union of Russian Engineers in France. Also includes materials on Boris M. Chetverukhin, Prince Aleksandr N. Iskander, Grand Duchess Olga Aleksandrovna, and Ivan S. Shmelev
    - 1951-1952. (Box 28)
      Includes materials on the Hermitage of Our Lady of Kursk in Mahopac, N.Y., the House of Free Russia, Inc., the Russian Anticommunist Center in New York, and Pavel A. Savich
    - 1952-1954. (Box 29)
      Includes materials on Vladimir K. Abdank-Kossovskii's exhibit "Zarubezhnaia Rus'," General Konstantin K. Agoev, M. A. Bozhenko-Karneeva, Russian cadet corps, Holy Trinity Monastery in Jordanville, N.Y., Prince Aleksandr N. Iskander, Resurrection Russian Orthodox Church in Meudon, France, ROVA Farms in New Jersey, and Russian veterans in Nice, France
    - 1954-1958. (Box 30)
      Includes materials on the Diocesan Assembly of the Russian Orthodox Church Outside Russia in May 1954, the Gallipoli Society, the Hermitage of Our Lady of Kursk, Holy Trinity Monastery, House of Free Russia in New York, Metropolitan Anastasii (Gribanovskii), General Viacheslav G. Naumenko, P. A. Savichs
    - 1954-1955. (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Archbishop Vitalii (Maksimenko), Bikhop Nikon (Rklitskii), Grand Duke Gavriil Konstantinovich, General Viacheslav G. Naumenko
    - 1956, 1958. (Box 32)
      Includes materials on Grand Duke Andrei Vladimirovich, Vladimir M. Despotuli, Georgii D. Grebenshchikov, Boris S. Koverda, Vsevolod K. Levashev (Dubrovskii), and the Tolstoy Foundation
    - 1959-1961. (Box 33)
      Includes materials on the consecration of the Synodal Cathedral of the Russian Orthodox Church Outside Russia in New York, and Grand Duchess Olga Aleksandrovna
  - Subject file. (Box 34)
    Includes clippings from émigré periodical publications, original documents, photographs, and other materials
    - Atlantis (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - Byzantium (Folder 34: 2)
    - Calendar reform (Folder 34: 3)
    - Carpatho-Rusyns (Folder 34: 4-6)
    - Cossacks (Folder 34: 7)
    - Den' Neprimiromosti (Folder 34: 8)
    - Displaced persons (Folder 34: 9)
    - Eichmann, Adolf. Relates to his trial in Jerusalem in 1961 (Folder 34: 10)
    - France (Folder 34: 11-12)
    - Freemasons (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - Grebenshchikov, Georgii Dmitrievich (Folder 35: 2)
    - Iskander, Aleksandr Nikolaevich, Prince. (Folder 35: 3)
      Includes biographical sketch, calling cards, correspondence
    - Katyn' Forest massacre (Folder 35: 4)
    - Kirill Vladimirovich, Grand Duke of Russia (Folder 35: 5)
    - Monarchy (Folder 35: 6-7)
    - Monarchy (Box-folder 36: 1-2)
    - Narodno-Trudovoi Soiuz (Folder 36: 3)
    - Nicholas II, 1894-1917 (Folder 36: 4-7)
    - Nicholas II (Box-folder 37: 1-5)
    - Numismatics (Folder 37: 6)
    - Ob"edinenie russkikh dvorian (Folder 37: 7)
    - Occult (Folder 37: 8)
    - Performing Arts (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - Philately (Folder 38: 2)
    - Red Cross (Folder 38: 3)
    - Romanov, House of. (Folder 38: 4-5)
      Includes materials on Imperial Family members in the diaspora
    - Russia
      - General (Folder 38: 6)
      - Anthropology (Folder 38: 7-10)
      - Anthropology (Box-folder 39: 1-3)
      - Cadet corps (Folder 39: 4)
      - Censorship, printing (Folder 39: 5)
      - Colonization of America (Folder 39: 6-7)
      - Feasts (Folder 39: 8)
      - National symbols (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
    - Russia--History--Revolution, 1917-1921
      - General (Folder 40: 3-4)
      - Intellectuals (Folder 40: 5)
    - Russia (Territory under White Armies, 1918-1920). North Russia. Orders and other documents signed by General Evgenii K. Miller (Folder 40: 6)
    - Russian Boy Scouts (Folder 40: 7)
    - Russian discoverers and inventors (Folder 40: 8)
    - Russian émigré organizations (Box 41)
      - General (Folder 41: 1)
      - Official forms (Folder 41: 2)
    - Russian émigré press (Folder 41: 3-4)
    - Russian fascists (Folder 41: 5)
    - Russian intelligentsia (Folder 41: 6)
    - Russian language. (Folder 41: 7-8)
      Includes materials on old orthography
    - Russian literature. (Folder 41: 9-10)
      Includes materials on Dostoevsky, Khomiakov, Pushkin, Tolstoy
    - Russian military émigrés (Box-folder 42: 1-2)
    - Russian Revolutionary Forces (Folder 42: 3)
    - Russian women (Folder 42: 4)
    - Russian youth organizations (Folder 42: 5)
    - Russians--Foreign countries
      - General (Folder 42: 6-7)
      - General (Box-folder 43: 1)
      - Albania (Folder 43: 2)
      - Africa. (Folder 43: 3-7)
        Includes materials on Abyssinia, Algeria, Egypt, South Africa, Tunis
      - Asia (Box-folder 44: 1)
      - Australia (Folder 44: 2-3)
      - Austria (Folder 44: 4)
      - Baltic states. (Folder 44: 5)
        Includes materials on Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania
      - Belgium (Folder 44: 6)
      - Bulgaria (Box-folder 45: 1)
      - China. (Folder 45: 2)
        See also Oversize file
      - Czechoslovakia (Folder 45: 3)
      - Europe. (Folder 45: 4)
        Includes materials on Denmark, Norway, Spain, Sweden, and Switzerland
      - France. (Folder 45: 5-7)
        Includes materials on Russians in Cannes, Grasses, Nice, Paris
      - France (Box-folder 46: 1-7)
      - France (Box-folder 47: 1-6)
      - France (Box-folder 48: 1)
      - Great Britain (Folder 48: 2)
      - Greece (Folder 48: 3)
      - Holland (Folder 48: 4)
      - Luxembourg (Folder 48: 5)
      - Poland (Folder 48: 6)
      - South America
        - Argentina (Folder 48: 7)
        - Brazil (Folder 48: 8)
        - Paraguay, Uruguay (Box-folder 49: 1)
      - Spain (Folder 49: 2)
      - Turkey (Folder 49: 3)
      - United States and North America
        - General (Folder 49: 4-5)
        - General (Box-folder 50: 1-5)
        - General (Box-folder 51: 1-3)
        - Cultural events (Folder 51: 4)
        - Performing arts (Folder 51: 5-6)
      - Yugoslavia (Folder 51: 7)
      - Yugoslavia (Box-folder 52: 1)
      - Russkaia osvoboditel'naia armiia (Folder 52: 2)
      - Russkaia pravoslavnaia tserkov'
        - General (Folder 52: 3)
        - Announcements (Folder 52: 4)
        - Baptism of Rus' anniversary (Folder 52: 5)
        - Bell ringing (Folder 52: 6)
        - Clergy (Folder 52: 7)
        - Destruction of churches (Folder 52: 8)
        - Institut St. Serge, Paris, France (Folder 52: 9)
      - Monasteries (Folder 52: 10)
      - Parishes in the diaspora (Box-folder 53: 1)
      - Russian Orthodox Church Outside Russia (Folder 53: 2)
    - Russkii korpus (Folder 53: 3)
    - Russkoe studencheskoe khristianskoe Dvizhenie (Folder 53: 4)
    - Separatism (Folder 53: 5)
    - Siberia and the Russian Far East (Folder 53: 6-8)
    - Slavs (Folder 53: 9)
    - Union pour la defense des peoples oprimes (Box-folder 54: 1)
    - Vserossiiskii soiuz russkikh natsional'nykh obshchin (Folder 54: 2)
  - Miscellany
    - Announcements (large format, 1914 and undated) (Folder 54: 3)
    - Calling cards (Folder 54: 4)
- Photographs, 1916-1961.
  142 prints, 12 negatives. Includes 1 print of Admiral A. V. Kolchak, 50 prints of Nicholas II and the Romanov family, 12 prints and 3 negatives of N. N. Pilevskii and associated individuals, 19 prints of Russian officers in emigration, 60 prints of Russian Orthodox churches and parish life, and 8 negatives of the "Zarubezhnaia Rus'" exhibit